

CONTACT

- Addres
 Cali, Colombia
- Phone +57-3187185350
- E-mail
 jaimehcadena@gmail.com
- in LinkedIn jaime-mendoza-0a297a10a

LANGUAGE

- Spanish
 Native
- English
 Intermediate

SOFT SKILLS

- Responsibility
- Teamwork
- Adaptability
- Time management
- Persistence
- Analysis
- Organization

JAIME CADENA

software engineer

PROFILE

Software engineer with more than 8 years of experience in analysis, design and development of applications using Java; following principles and philosophy of clean code, different styles of architecture and agile methodologies, attentive to adaptability and performance. Passionated about software development, results driven, excellent interpersonal skills, proactive, focused on improving the company's results. I am seeking a senior software engineer role, which will enable me to contribute to the growth of the company with my skills and experience and excel in my carrer path.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

dLocal I Montevideo, Uruguay

2021 - Present

project: fraud prevention, responsible for assessing the level of risk present in each transaction

TECH LEAD

Tech and Solve I Medellín, Colombia

2020 - 2021

project: digital transformation of sales, responsible of supporting client affiliation to pension, severance, savings and investment products offered by the company

TECH LEAD

PersonalSoft I Medellin, Colombia

2019 - 2020

project: digital transformation, responsible of managing medical appointments and clinical history

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Pragma I Medellín, Colombia

2018 - 2019

project: SOAT digital transformation, responsible for supporting the accident insurance acquisition process.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Smart TMT I Cali, Colombia

2017 - 2018

project: Aire portal, responsable of collect different types of taxes

PARADIGMS

- Object-oriented programming
- Functional programming
- Reactive Programming

SOME CONCEPTS, PRACTICES, PRINCIPLES

- · Clean code
- Test-Driven Development
- Domain-Driven design
- Continuous Integration
- Continuous Delivery
- SOLID
- Persitence
- Circuit Breaker
- Git Flow
- Refactor
- · Api Gateway
- Service Discovery
- Distributed Tracing
- Audit
- Health Check
- Dependency management

EXPERIENCE

TEACHER - SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

SENA I Bogotá, Colombia

2014 - 2018

project: SAF, responsible of support academic and administrative processes in an educational center

To impart professional training in software development

EDUCATION

2016

System Engineer

Institución Universitaria Antonio José Camacho

2017

Specialization in strategic information technology management Universidad Santiago de Cali

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Java	Javascript	Sql
PHP		

FRAMEWORKS

Spring MVC	Spring Boot 2	Micronaout
Dropwizard	React	Angular

DATABASES

Postgresql	Oracle	MySql
Redis	DynamoDB	MongoDB

TOOLS

Kibana	Splunk	NewRelic
Jira	Jenkins	SonarQube
SonarLint	Intellij IDEA	Postman
SoapUI	Artifactory	Bitbucket
Github	Fluid Attacks	Docker

CLOUD SERVICES

Amazon SNS	Amazon SQS	Amazon S3
Amazon Kinesis	Amazon Athena	Amazon ECS
Amazon Parameter S.	Amazon RDS	Amazon ECS